{
    "id": "3d25c82158bf445986fe3522eed09ce6",
    "title": "Subordinate Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I did it because I wanted to.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of reason is usually introduced by a conjunction like as, since or because.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "01e8352ef32d4b3f9d99a011d1ffbe30"
        },
        {
            "question": "As he was not there, I spoke to his mother.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of reason is usually introduced by a conjunction like as, since or because.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4aad60e5027e449bad7218fb7381cfbe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Just as he entered the room, the clock struck eleven.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of time shows the time of the action mentioned in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3b977aa6d3b246cdb3d01543296b96a6"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you eat too much you will fall ill.",
            "description": "Adverb clauses of condition are usually introduced by the subordinating conjunctions if or unless.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "95ff94b47f824f8292bfee8218bc95a8"
        },
        {
            "question": "We asked him many questions when he returned.",
            "description": "An adverb clause of time shows the time of the action mentioned in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7baf234dfdd2460ca1e0d2c58fc19261"
        },
        {
            "question": "My parents were poor though they were of noble birth.",
            "description": "Adverb clauses of concession or contrast are usually introduced by the conjunctions though and although.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1e5b397ebb21452b8f77d14dc20c3488"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mary had a little lamb whose fleece was as white as snow.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause ‘whose fleece was as white as snow’ modifies the noun lamb.",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "edf911f5a437437e9b884be9f60a7a39"
        },
        {
            "question": "I still live in the same city where I was born.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause 'where I was born' modifies the noun city.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a20f49f1c419459ab8270fb2225de593"
        },
        {
            "question": "He met a girl whose eyes were blue.",
            "description": "Here the adjective clause whose eyes were blue modifies the noun girl.",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "dd17d9bba6cc40eea3ead8c69ecbcd8a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I often wonder how you are getting on.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause ‘how you are getting on’ acts as the object of the verb wonder. ",
            "answers": [
                "Adverb clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d7984ddd04334504b7dbde88a6528053"
        },
        {
            "question": "He asked me where I lived.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause ‘where I lived’ acts as the object of the verb asked. ",
            "answers": [
                "Noun clause",
                "Adjective clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "30db17bcaa684fcd965512685cf05aa3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The fact that he is silent proves his guilt.",
            "description": "Here the noun clause 'the fact that he is silent' is the object of the verb proves. ",
            "answers": [
                "Adjective clause",
                "Noun clause",
                "Adverb clause"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "64e2cdc03a5b4685ab6ea17bd394e08e"
        }
    ]
}